<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Noam Lerner's Blog</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Noam Lerner's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:11:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bugok.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Over engineering file transfer</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/over_engineering_file_transfer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:11:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/over_engineering_file_transfer/</guid><description>Context On Thursdays, I take my younger daughter to a swimming lessons. Sometimes, I take my GoPro with me. I take a video during the lesson and when I get home I edit the video, upload and share it with friends and family. In the last few days, I realized that I may not be able to connect mass storage devices to my laptop, so I tried to find another solution to transfer the files from my GoPro to my laptop.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a custom domain for github pages</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/setting_up_a_custom_domain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:14:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/setting_up_a_custom_domain/</guid><description>In the last few days, I had to take some sick time from work and attend to my kids who are at home while my wife isn&amp;rsquo;t feeling well. After spending all day running after them, I needed to unwind at the evening. I played some Eleven Table Tennis and then went to play around with creating a custom domain for the blog, instead of having it being served from bugok.</description></item><item><title>The bus factor, during the pandemic</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/the_bus_factor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 13:44:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/the_bus_factor/</guid><description>The definition of the bus factor from wikipedia says:
The bus factor is a measurement of the risk resulting from information and capabilities not being shared among team members, derived from the phrase &amp;ldquo;in case they get hit by a bus&amp;rdquo;.
When thinking about the team structure, having a SPOF (Single Point Of Failure) as a single person - isn&amp;rsquo;t something desirable. &amp;ldquo;What if X gets hit by a bus?</description></item><item><title>Handling the low tide</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/handling_low_tide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:44:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/handling_low_tide/</guid><description>There are times where you have no other choice but to take your foot off the gas, and still be at work. You&amp;rsquo;re not taking time off, but you can&amp;rsquo;t do the work you usually do. Examples for reasons which can cause these are: code freeze, a holiday season or a shift in direction.
Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to be in this situations. I like sitting at my desk knowing what&amp;rsquo;s the next thing I need to tackle.</description></item><item><title>I'm the tech lead, I can create panic</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/im_the_tech_lead_i_can_create_panic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 20:41:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/im_the_tech_lead_i_can_create_panic/</guid><description>This post is the first real post I had in mind when thinking to start the blog. Is started with a random conversation with a friend who&amp;rsquo;s a tech lead at a big company. We met by chance one morning, and we discussed how different the working environment has become since the pandemic started, and how &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo; has changed in many aspects when everyone, or some, are working remotely.
Building connections and trust when working remotely Building connections and trust between team members has become harder since the pandemic started.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a blog using Hugo and Github pages</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/setting_up_a_hugo_blog_with_github_pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 21:43:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/setting_up_a_hugo_blog_with_github_pages/</guid><description>In this first post, in an inception-like manner, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I got this blog to work.
Starting point This started with a Facebook group post which asked what is a good platform to host a blog. There were a few answers, but the hugo and github pages caught my eye, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;ll give it a go.
I Googled a bit and found this guide. That was a good starting point, as it allowed me to get something to work - but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully happy with the end result.</description></item><item><title>Be nice, especially when you don't want to be</title><link>https://bugok.github.io/post/be_nice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bugok.github.io/post/be_nice/</guid><description>This statement was given in a &amp;lsquo;conflict resolution&amp;rsquo; class I took a few months ago. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about that class, but this statement stuck. Mostly, I think, is because I sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t do it - but when I do - I feel really good about myself.
What I think I want In heated settings, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to lose temper. For me, this usually comes because of frustration of not getting agreed with.</description></item></channel></rss>